[Music]
Welcome back to Corporate Connection.  Thanks for staying with us.
Now let's talk to the management of ICICI LBD
and have the company's second quarter
results been better?
Where did they get support in their strong results?
What is the growth outlook for FY26?
What are the plans for recovery at Group Health?
How much boost has the sector received from GST reform
?
ICICI Lombard's
CFO Gopal Balachandran is joining us to discuss all these things.  So Gopal ji,
thank you for being with us and
thank you for your time.  First,
tell us what your outlook is for FY26
?
If we talk about all the rates, what will be your expectations for the
second half, for your paid growth,
for net in earned premium and for all other
factors like combined ratio, please
share it with our viewers
before I get up the answer, I
want to give season greeting to all the viewers and this
atmosphere is quite good.  So I think
collectively all of us will be able to spend
quality time together.  But now let's come back
to business.  If you have seen
from an isolation standpoint in business,
what has been our underwriting philosophy.  We have always
focused on driving profitable
growth is the theme that we have largely been kind
of driving as a company.  And this is
not a recent thing.  Even for the last
several years I think last largely what we were able
to drive is profitable growth as a
theme.  And this is what you will see.  Even as
you look into the second half of the year, we will
continue to look for across businesses.
We will look at how we are able to kind of write
profitable risk across
categories.  Specifics: What you are saying in
terms of how will the growth be?  How will the
combined ratios be, how will our
profitability be, ROES extra, which
we are seeing right now, I think we are seeing a
lot of positive momentum in the context
of IC LB across businesses, if you
look at motor, health or commercial lines,
I think the growth momentum is
looking quite good for us and that is also getting
exhibited, if you have seen the
numbers of September month,
our growth on commercial lines has been quite
good, even the relative gap between motor
growth and industry growth has
reduced considerably.  And retail health is the
segment we have always focused on right now.
That has again kind of done very
well.  So across the streams I think we have been able to kind of do a
good job and we and the
government and the regulators have done a pretty
good job in terms of the range of
reforms that they have announced.  Which also adds up
very well in terms of how one
looks at growth potential for the second half
of the year.  And as far as our expectation
of combined ratio slush profitability is concerned,
our expectation is
that we should continue to see an improvement
in combined ratios compared to what we have been
reporting, but monetarily we have said earlier
that our return on equity
range that we are
comfortable with is between 18 to
20%, so what we want to kind
of deliver return on equity on a
sustained basis and that is something that we
will actively kind of look at in terms
of delivering even as we look at for the
future.
Of course Gopal Saheb will come to you but
here are two important news which will be
very important to tell the viewers.  First of all, let us take a look at the IRSFC
results that are coming.
Where the profits have increased.
We have seen the figure of Rs 1777 crore coming.
If we look at the numbers on year on year basis,
this figure has increased from 1777 crores to 1613 crores
year on year.  NII has
also seen an increase and
this figure is ₹1828 crores pay year on year and IRFC is
also seen announcing a dividend of ₹1 per share here
and the counter is currently trading with a strength of about 1.5%
but has made a profit
and the numbers are looking good on the income front as well.
We can see a profit number coming here, increasing from Rs 1651 crore to Rs 1828 crore and NII
income has also increased here on year on year basis,
however, we will have to see quarter on quarter
how the numbers perform
and we will analyse it later
but let us move ahead and my next
question to Gopal saheb is on gross premiums,
sir, where we have
seen a slight decrease of around 12%
quarter on quarter but if you
want to explain this then how will you explain it?
So our business is quite cyclical.
And as I said, whatever the growth
percentages are, whether low or high, it is
purely driven by what we are seeing in
terms of the market opportunities.  Ah,
if the market environment is quite good in
terms of pricing regime, then ICICI always
you will see ah seeing an increase in market
share, but if in any segments, if there is a lot more
competitive intensity and
elevated pricing is getting
reflected, then during that time ICIC
generally tends to take a back seat and we will be slightly more
guarded and in that
period, we will be quite also okay to let go
of market share because whenever
pricing remains quite aggressive
in the market.  It Does Not Make Sense for Us
to Kind of Go Very Aggressive in Writing
Risk.  So here we will largely kind of
protect our capital and there kind of
significantly drive profitable
growth segments.  So that's been our approach
in terms of how one wants to kind of
write the portfolio.  And that and the
quarter on quarter that you have talked about,
as I said, our
business remains quite cyclical.  For example, in quarter one it
is more inclined towards
corporates.  Typically, the
policy period and
financial period of the policies of corporates generally mirror
each other.  But in quarter two and
quarter three generally you will see that a
lot more businesses are returning towards
retail lines and also some of the crop
businesses get booked.  A so better way to look at is more
quarter to two quarter to two of
the same periods.  On that, if you would have noticed
that our growth could be relatively
muted on a quarter to quarter basis but
monetarily I think the quality of risk that
we are underwriting is very very
positive.  But more than quarter two I think what one
wants to speak about is I
think the momentum that we're heading into
quarter three and thereafter.  Ah
particularly for the month of September.  I
think we have been able to kind of do a lot of
positive
growth opportunities at one is seeing and hence to that
extent we think we are very very
well positioned to be able to capitalize on this
opportunity of growth.
Okay and Gopal ji, please explain to us that on one hand
your net profit has increased but on the other hand
your underwriting losses are still at a very
high level, so please explain to us
what steps are you taking to reduce this loss
?
[Applause]
That's a good question too.  Sometimes it keeps
coming again and again at different points
of time.  Let me tell all the viewers that there is
a particular
news on the reporting of general insurance financials.  For example, if
you take a policy for the last 12 months, the
earnings of that policy which the general insurance company reflects are
over the policy period.  But the
insurance companies that incur cost, the
accounting of acquisition cost for acquiring a policy is done immediately.  The
policy is
expensed at the same time it is sourced.
So if you
give absolute underwriting outcome of any general
insurance company financials then you will
always see an adverse outcome.  So
instead of looking at the absolute
outcomes of underwriting, a better measure to
look at is more the combined
ratios and less specifically the return
on equity that a general company is
exhibiting.  And there you must have seen
for ICB, for example, the
combined ratios we reported for quarter two of last year
was 104.5%. The
same number, if you looked at it on an end
basis, which is a like-to-like basis, for
quarter two of this year,
our combined ratio was 103.9%. So
clearly, we have been able to see an
improvement in the combined ratios on a
like-to-like basis when you look at
quarter two of last year to quarter two
of the current year. Similarly, if you
looked at our return on equity, as
I said, the range ICB is
comfortable with is delivering
ROE on a sustained basis in the range of 18
to 20%. If you looked at the ROE for quarter two,
it has been slightly more than 20%. So, we are very,
very happy with the way
things have played out for ICB.  Lobbard
Weather You Look At In The Context Of
Combined Ratios And For The Matter Of Even
ROEs.
Okay Gopal ji, thank you very much for your time and for
answering our questions.
Before wrapping up the show, let's
address the flashes that are coming on Tikkar.